Okay, so in this lesson then, I'm going to
give you a class overview and really
explain what to expect out of these video
lessons.
Okay.
Now, the P&P exam is very challenging.
Make sure you understand that.
This is a challenging exam.
It's not an easy exam by any means.
You have to study.
you have to put in the time to study.
However, you also need to have the right
mindset and the right approach to study.
You need to understand
how to first approach
this class and how to study afterwards.
Okay, and that really is what this lesson
is all about.
Now, there are many, many different ways
of managing a project.
Right.
Different industries manage projects
differently.
An IT project, for example, is managed
very differently to a construction
project, which is managed very differently
to a marketing project, which is managed
very differently to a research and development
project or a pharmaceutical project.
Every industry manages projects
differently.
There's many, many different methodologies
out there.
There's no right or wrong way of managing
a project.
There's obviously a good and bad way of
managing a project, but there are many,
many different ways, many different
methodologies and different industries,
different organizations manage projects
their own way.
Now, there's many factors that go into how
you manage your project as well,
such as, for example, geographical
location.
You're going to manage
a project differently in one
part of the world compared
to another part of the world.
Just for example, there might be some
cultural differences, regulatory differences.
So even the same
project, you'd be managing
differently in another part of the world.
Now, what PMI have done is, they've taken
all these different factors into
consideration, all these factors that
impact your project and all these factors
we're going to be discussing as we go
through these video lessons.
What PMI have done is taking all these
factors into consideration and really
created their own generic standard,
if you like.
They've created a standard for project
management or a framework
for project management.
And it's the standard and framework that
is documented in PIMBOC.
So every few years they update those
standards.
So currently the latest
version of PIMBOC that's
being tested on the exam
is PIMBOC version 6.
Now here's something very important to
understand.
The PMP exam is testing your
knowledge and understanding of
PMI's standards is testing your
knowledge and understanding
of the PMI framework
of project management.
That's all the PMP exam is testing.
It is not testing how good of a project
manager you are.
It is not testing how
well you manage projects
in your organisation or in your industry.
The PMP exam is testing your knowledge and
understanding of PMI's standards,
of PMI's framework.
And that's what this class is about.
This class is here purely and simply,
we are preparing you to pass the P&P exam.
I'm not preparing you to manage a project.
I'm not teaching you how to manage a
project.
We are going to teach you how to pass the
PMP exam.
And that's something very, very important
to understand because now you basically
almost have to unlearn everything you've
learned about project management.
You have to put that at the back of your
mind.
Right, and why?
Well, because you have to think in terms
of PMI standards now.
You have to think the PMI way.
When you are answering a question,
right, typically you'll get scenario
question, multiple choice
or before option choices,
and one of those option
choices will be correct.
Typically, what's going to happen?
It's very tempting.
Look at the option choices and choose the
best option that you would take or the
best approach that you would take in your
line of work.
But you have to take a step back because
that might not be in
line with PMI standards.
you always have to think which of these is
in line with PMI standards.
So, as I said, you almost have to unlearn
everything you've learned
about project management.
You have to put that at the back of your
mind and start thinking PMI standards.
Now, some of these standards you might not
agree with.
There's some stuff that
we are going to be teaching
you that you might not
necessarily agree with.
In fact, there's a whole
bunch of stuff we're going
to teach you that I don't
necessarily agree with.
Kimberly doesn't necessarily
agree with, but it makes no
difference whether we agree
or whether we don't agree.
When you are answering a
PMP exam question, you have to
answer it based on their
standards, based on PMI standards.
And that's something very, very important
to understand.
So part of passing the PMP exam is exam
technique.
There's a lot of curveballs that PMI throw
at you on the exam.
They'll give you irrelevant information or
they'll give you.
give you irrelevant scenarios altogether,
right?
So you need to be able to learn to pick
out keywords and key phrases.
You need to be able to navigate through
these ambiguous questions.
Many questions are going to be ambiguous.
You're reading the question.
Sometimes you're
wondering what they're even
asking or you're
looking at option choices.
They all look good.
They all look correct.
So there might be just one
keyword here and there that's
separating the correct answer
from the wrong answers.
So you need to learn how to pick out those
keywords.
And again, something we're going to be
covering during this class.
Now, the only way of learning all of that
is by going through practice questions.
You need to practice what you learn.
Now, many of you are aware that the exam
changed in 2021.
So now there are three domains.
We talk about three domains.
right you have something called the people
domain right the process domain and the
business environment domain right so the
exam is based off of those three domains
now the old PIMBOC domains though so the
PIMBOC guide right so a sixth edition is
really currently what is being tested or
the exam is partly based off of the sixth
edition there was five process groups
initiating planning execute monitoring
controlling and closing you still need to
know that, right?
You still need to be aware of the
processes, right?
But one of the other things that PMI added
to the exam or changed in January of 2021
is the fact that now 50% of the exam is
agile and 50% is predictive, right?
Predictive is your traditional waterfall
style of project management, right,
whereas agile is a completely different
approach.
And they're almost like two conflicting
approaches to project management.
However, you need to know both approaches.
50% of the exam is agile, 50% is
predictive.
So the PIMBOC guide really refers to the
predictive side.
The PIMBOC guide doesn't really have as
much bearing on agile
as it does predictive.
We always recommend becoming
a member of PMI and then
you can download a free
copy of the PIMBock guide.
And you can also download a free copy of
the Agile Practice Guide as well.
And for both of them, we just recommend
using them as a reference guide.
So the PinBock Guide, version 6,
and the Agile Practice Guide, you can
download them for free from the PMI.org
website if you remember of PMI.
And then those are useful resources just
as a reference guide.
Okay.
So one of the key things, though,
to understand, right?
The PIMBock Guide is not a textbook.
It's not a textbook for managing a
project.
It's not a textbook for passing the PMP
exam.
The PIMBOT guide is just there as a
framework.
Right.
It's just a reference guide
for project managers,
just setting the standards
for project management.
That's really all it is.
And really, it's just setting the
standards for predictive projects.
So remember you need to understand both
predictive and agile.
So make sure then you can think in terms
of PMI and when you take in the exam you
have to think in terms of
PMI's standards and you have
to think in terms of both
predictive as well as agile.